<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IvanF.</title>
    <link>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on IvanF.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.ivanferdelja.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Liquor Cabinet</title>
      <link>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/project/liquor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/project/liquor/</guid>
      <description>Bridge is a need-based search, communication, and networking tool that helps you find and access the right person for whatever you need, leveraging the network effect (“six degrees of separation”) of your friends and colleagues.
Bridge is also an omnipresent social capital exchange / platform / wallet, keeping track of &amp;ldquo;favors” between people, estimating how close the a person is to everyone in his or her network (phonebook) and establishing virtual currency that represents the &amp;ldquo;social capital&amp;rdquo; of each user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridge for iOS and Android</title>
      <link>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/archive/bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/archive/bridge/</guid>
      <description>Bridge is a need-based search, communication, and networking tool that helps you find and access the right person for whatever you need, leveraging the network effect (“six degrees of separation”) of your friends and colleagues.
Bridge is also an omnipresent social capital exchange / platform / wallet, keeping track of &amp;ldquo;favors” between people, estimating how close the a person is to everyone in his or her network (phonebook) and establishing virtual currency that represents the &amp;ldquo;social capital&amp;rdquo; of each user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AgentCASH Smart POS</title>
      <link>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/project/agent-cash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/project/agent-cash/</guid>
      <description>AgentCASH  is a mobile payment system for Android that allows businesses to accept card or cash payments any place, any time.
App fully supports all requirements of a small or medium business.
Some of the features:
 add, edit and organise all products or services into a neat, clean and visually informative page system run cash or card payments (via a Bluetooth card reader) print receipts or issue them by e-mail and text messages manage customers and invoices</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PatchUp</title>
      <link>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/project/patchup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/project/patchup/</guid>
      <description>PatchUp for iOS is a an app for micro-reporting in the cities, targeting US region starting with Seattle.
App is scheduled to launch at the Seattle Designing cities convention
PatchUp platform

 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color tab concept</title>
      <link>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/project/colored-tabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/project/colored-tabs/</guid>
      <description>Colored Tabs is a concept Android app to explore aspects of Material design such as immersion, cards etc.
Design created by Vedran Židanik.
Source available on GitHub.
Tech note: Story feed video content is displayed on a TextureView instead of SurfaceView. Considering SurfaceView is rendered in a separate window from the app, artifacts were clearly visible while scrolling in either direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrofit internals</title>
      <link>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/post/retrofit-internals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/post/retrofit-internals/</guid>
      <description>The great Retrofit library by Square has by now become an industry standard. Here is little scratch beneath the surface to understand some of its design decisions.
Retrofit internals diagram</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I love Square but night clubs might not</title>
      <link>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/post/square-nightclubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/post/square-nightclubs/</guid>
      <description>At 2AM on a cold Saturday night I was standing on the upper level of a nightclub, observing the party below. The dance floor has gone wild and the bar is crowded. Behind the bar, couple of waiters were running wild trying to keep up with the orders. And they were doing a damn good job. I wondered how long it would take for me to get this good. The POS software they used was the most popular POS in Adriatic nightclubs and restaurants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trust is in the details</title>
      <link>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/post/pieces-of-plastic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/post/pieces-of-plastic/</guid>
      <description>Having worked with card payment solutions, I formed a habit of noticing the POS hardware when waiting in line at the register.
Konzum (largest supermarket chain in Croatia) and IKEA Zagreb both use the same POS terminal made by the French company Ingenico. Terminal is also supplied with an optional PIN privacy shield to provide the customer with additional confidentiality.
Unlike Konzum, IKEA decided to buy the optional shield.
 This might not seem like a big deal, but card frauds don&amp;rsquo;t just happen to people you read about, they are real.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The time I called and they didn&#39;t care</title>
      <link>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/post/customer-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ivanferdelja.com/post/customer-care/</guid>
      <description>At quarter past eleven on a Wednesday night we learned that one of our customers had run into a problem. We decided not to wait solving it. Few minutes later, as I was leaving my apartment, I decided to use a popular app to get myself a taxi. As I walked down the staircase from the top floor of my building I got the notification - a car was on its way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>